跟着我在这里转一圈 朗耶尔城（挪威城市）
Come take a walk with me around Longyearbyen.
那是挪威斯瓦尔巴群岛上最大的城镇。
That's the largest town on the Norwegian islands of Svalbard.
其中某些场景可能看上去很熟悉。
Parts of it may loo k familiar.
但毫无疑问
But make no mistake,
这个地方是与众不同的
this place is different.
北纬七十八度
At seventy eight degrees North,
它离北极只有八百英里或13公里
it is just eight hundred miles or thirteen hundred kilometers from the North Pole.
有超过二千的常住居民
And with over two thousand permanent residents,
它是地球上最北部的城镇。
it is the northernmost real town on Earth.
公路总长仅有50公里
There are only fifty kilometers of road,
包括房子之间的小街道
including the small streets between houses,
所以人们在这里
so people get around the island,
主要是通过雪地摩托出行
mainly on snowmobile.
事实上
In fact,
这里注册的雪地摩托比居民还多
there are more registered snowmobiles than residents.
任何人离开小镇的时候都需要随身携带一把枪，并且要知道如何使用
Anyone leaving town is required to travel with a gun and someone who knows how to use it.
因为这些岛屿也是北极熊的家园。
Because the islands are also home to polar bears.
白天的平均气温低于零度
The average daytime high is below freezing for all,
但一年中的四个月
but four months of the year.
从十月末到二月中旬
And from the end of October to mid February,
太阳都不会升起
the sun doesn't rise at all.
这是一个漫长的极地之夜
This is the long polar night.
住在这里很困难
Living here is tough.
去年12月
This past December,
城里的雪崩摧毁了十户人家
an avalanche in town destroyed ten homes,
以前就是在这里
which used to be here.
两人失去了生命
Killing two people.
那么 这个寒冷的遥远的冰雪覆盖的群岛是如何居住的呢
So how did this cold remote ice covered Archipelago come to be inhabited?
城镇周围的山丘蕴藏着丰富的煤矿 已经开采了一百多年
The hills around town are rich in coal deposits that have been mined for over a hundred years.
煤是通过一系列的空中运输方式运到港口的
The coal was transported to the port by a series of aerial tramways,
其中一些仍然存在
some of which remain today,
尽管他们已经不再使用了
though they are no longer operational.
煤炭是一个提醒，它的斯瓦尔巴特群岛并不总是北极的冰世界。
Coal is a reminder that its Svalbard was not always an Arctic ice world.
3.6亿年前 它实际上是在热带地区
Three hundred and sixty million years ago it was actually in the tropics,
就在赤道以北
just north of the equator,
一个沼泽区 上面覆盖着现代蕨类植物的前体细胞
a swampy area it was covered with the precursors to modern ferns,
它们比现在大得多
which were much larger than they are today.
高度达到10到30米
reaching ten to thirty meters in height.
然后 这些植被被泥土和沙子覆盖 淹没在海底
This vegetation was then covered in mud and sand and submerged under the sea.
随着时间的推移
Over time,
它变成了20世纪从挪威带来矿工的煤矿
it turned into the coal deposits that in the twentieth century brought miners from Norway,
俄罗斯和美国
Russia and the US.
大多数煤矿现在已经关闭 经济正逐渐转向旅游业
Most of the coal mines have now closed and the economy is gradually shifting towards tourism,
教育和研究
education and research.
游客们乘坐雪地摩托和狗雪橇旅行
The tourists take trips on snowmobiles and dog sleds.
在斯瓦尔巴有一个大学中心
There is a university centre in Svalbard,
它提供生物学的学期课程
which offers semester courses in biology,
物理和地质学
physics and geology.
在山的一侧是斯瓦尔巴全球种子库。
And up on the side of a mountain is the Svalbard global seed vault.
但这是另一个时代的故事
But that's a story for another time.
当地人告诉我 来自不同国家的地区对该地区的兴趣正在增加
The locals tell me that interest in the region from different nations is increasing.
随着全球变暖 北极冰层缩小
As the globe warms and Arctic ice shrinks,
整个北部的贸易路线正在开放
trade routes are opening up across the North.
斯瓦尔巴特群岛被战略性地安置在北美，
And Svalbard is strategically placed between North America,
亚洲和欧洲
Asia and Europe.
所以在未来的某一天，
So one day in the future,
斯瓦尔巴群岛可能不再像以前那样寒冷或遥远。
Svalbard may no longer be as cold or as remote as it once was.
但现在它提醒我们
But for now it is a reminder of how,
通过我们的聪明才智
through our ingenuity,
人们可以住在最不适宜居住的地方
people can live in the most inhospitable of places.